Indiana University DBA Program Chair's records, 1965-1971 C324
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University DBA Program Chair's records
1965-1971
1967-1971
Indiana University Archives
Indiana University. Graduate School of Business
C324
1 cubic foot 3 boxes
The doctoral program in IU's School of Business dates from 1947 when a Ph.D. was approved by the university trustees. Since that time, over 1,000 candidates have graduated from the program. This collection contains files dating from the tenure of Schuyler F. Otteson as chairman of the doctoral program (1965-1971), and includes correspondence and administrative files.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.
Administrative History
The School of Commerce and Finance (now the Kelley School of Business) was established at Indiana University in 1920 with Professor William A. Rawles as dean. Since this time, the school has grown from an initial enrollment of 70 students in 1920 to over 8,000 students in undergraduate, graduate, and online programs, on two campuses, both full- and part-time.
The school's doctoral program dates from just after World War II. In June 1947, the IU trustees authorized the Doctor of Commercial Science degree, which was later changed to a Doctor of Business Administration. The D.C.S. degree required candidates to be competent in five fields, including economic theory. Written and oral examinations in those fields and the preparation of a dissertation completed the degree requirements. In 1948-1949, there were 28 D.C.S. candidates. Since its inception, the doctoral program in the School of Business has graduated more than 1,000 students.
Arrangement
Collection is organized into two series: Correspondence and Administrative files.
Scope and Content Note
This small collection of records date from Schuyler F. Otteson's tenure as chair of the Doctoral program in Business Administration, 1965-1971.
The first series, Correspondence (.1 cubic foot), spans the years 1965-1971 and is arranged alphabetically by subject or correspondent's surname. Overall, the correspondence is very general in nature and primarily consists of communications with department members or those in the same field at other universities, such as Robert C. Harding, Head of the Dept. of Business Administration at the University of Alaska.
The second series, Administrative files (.7 cubic feet), spans the years 1965-1971 and includes files on various subjects relating to the DBA chair position such as grants, enrollment, and committees. The folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Separated Material
These records were separated from Prof. Otteson's personal papers (Collection C290).
Related Material
Additional records such as newsletters, annual reports, bulletins, and publications may be accessed in the Archives of Institutional Memory
Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database
Acquisition Information
Accession numbers: 2005/101
Provenance
Transferred from Kelley School of Business in September 2005.
Business schools --Indiana --History --20th century.; Business --Study and teaching (Higher) --Indiana --Archives.; Otteson, Schuyler F. (Schuyler Franklin), 1917-; Indiana University. Graduate School of Business -- Curricula -- Archives; Indiana University. Graduate School of Business -- Curricula -- Records and correspondence; Indiana University. Graduate School of Business -- Curricula -- History -- Sources
- Correspondence, 1965-1971 (Box 1)
  - "A" General, 1967-1970 (Box 1)
  - "B" General, 1967-1970 (Box 1)
  - "C" General, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
  - "D" General, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
  - "E" General, 1967-1970 (Box 1)
  - "F" General, 1967 (Box 1)
  - "G" General, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
  - "H" General, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - "I" General, 1967-1969 (Box 1)
  - "J" General, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - "K" General, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - "L" General, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - "Mc" General, 1965-1968 (Box 1)
  - "M" General, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - "N" General, 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - "P" General, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
  - "R" General, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
- Administrative files, 1965-1971
  - Administrative Communications Committee (Box 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 1)
    - Minutes, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
  - Bloomington Faculty Council, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Business Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - DBA Conference (IU Sesquicentennial) (Box 1)
    - Feb. 1969- Feb. 1970 (Box 1)
    - March – April 1970 (Box 1)
  - DBA Program and Committee (Box 2)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 2)
    - 1967 (Box 2)
  - DBA Research Seminars, 1967-1970 (Box 2)
  - Enrollment, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
  - Europe Trip (Italy and Spain), 1970 (Box 2)
  - European Doctoral Fellowship Program in Management Education (Box 2)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 2)
    - Applicants, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
  - Evans, Daniel F. – President, L.S. Ayres & Co., 1969 (Box 2)
  - Executive Program, 1971 (Box 2)
  - External Fellowships Committee, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Faculty Annual Summary Report, 1965-1969 (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation Awards, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - John Edwards Fellowship Committee, 1967-1970 (Box 2)
  - National Defense Education Act (NDEA) (Box 2)
    - Grant Materials (Box 2)
      - 1967-April 1968 (Box 2)
      - May 1968-1972 (Box 3)
    - Title IV Grant Application, ca., 1968 (Box 3)
  - Quantitative Business Analysis, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Report on Undergraduate, MBA, and DBA Programs, 1969-1970 (Box 3)
  - Research Seminar Attendance, Summer 1967 (Box 3)
  - University Graduate School, 1968 (Box 3)